DANIEL CHOINIERE

WEB DEVELOPER | RECORD LABEL ASSOCIATE

Profile: Multi-talented problem solver with 8+ years of professional experience (2 years in part-time web development) seeking full time developer position. Highly motivated to begin contributing to a high-performing team and expanding technical skill set.

CONTACT

ADDRESS:

7608 Landau Dr. Bloomington, MN 55438

EMAIL:

dchoinie@gmail.com

PHONE:

(651) 208-2707

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/daniel-choiniere

WEBSITE:

dchoinie.github.io

Technical Skills

Solid Skils:

HTML

CSS / SASS

JavaScript

jQuery

Bootstrap

Skills In Development:

PHP

MySQL

Angular.js

React.is

Node.is

Tools:

Visual Studio GitHub WordPress Shopify

Education

McNally Smith College of Music

AAS in Music Business

Gustavus Adolphus College

TeamTrehouse.com

References

Available upon request

EXPERIENCE

K-TEL INTERNATIONAL, LTD

Record Label Associate | 2014 - Present

- Created E-commerce website utilizing the Shopify platform resulting in 60%+ increase in online sales.
- Designed & developed custom landing pages for social media contests.
- Implemented online registration process for multiple free & paid events.
- Implemented use of Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel to track conversions on website.
- · Create and distribute mass email marketing campaigns including A/B testing.
- · Head of online paid advertising campaigns (FB/Insta/Google Adwords).
- · Perform audio, video and image editing with basic graphic design.

PUBLICINDOORTENNIS.COM

Developer/Tennis Professional | 2011 - Present

- · Led initiative to overhaul entire frontend to optimize the UI / UX.
- Work with owner to determine project scope and create mock-ups of new UI / UX utilizing Balsamig Mock-Ups.
- Designed, developed and maintain all frontend aspects of company website.
- · Leveraged the Bootstrap framework to transform site to be fully responsive.
- · Directly communicate with clients in group and private settings.

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Web Developer | 2016 - Present

- · Leveraged the WordPress CMS to create multiple small business websites for client.
- Assisted in gathering media assets for use on web and social media platforms.
- Utilized 3rd party plug-in to enable online membership purchases.
- Perform online marketing services including management of placements on 3rd party booking websites and popular online directories resulting in over 75% increase in bookings.